### **EVAN DANA**

Sr. Software Engineer Boston, MA ☑ evan.writes.code@gmail.com

@evandana

n evandana

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH A FOCUS ON ARCHITECTING SUCCESSFUL WEB EXPERIENCES. Approaches challenges with engaging energy and passion, engineering efficient tooling, processes, and organization to benefit the project and team. Articulate technical and cross-domain communication enhanced by design background.

# **Work History**

## General Electric | GE Digital

Sr. Software Engineer

ES6, Polymer, NodeJS, CI/CD, Hexagonal Architecture, Domain Modeling

🛗 2016 - Present | 🕈 Boston, MA

# Publicis.Sapient | Sapient Consulting

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2

ES6, AngularJS 1.x, Aurelia, Agile, Atomic Design, JSPM, NodeJS, Continuous Integration, Hexagonal Architecture (server-side), Domain-Driven Development, Domain Modeling

🛗 2013 - 2016 | 🕈 Boston, MA

Delivered complex features in a timely manner, independently and through collaboration, with utmost attention to quality. Exemplified best practices from coding patterns to agile methodologies. Translated requirements into manageable stories with clear and complete acceptance criteria, raising discussions early if needed.

Mentored software engineers and presented on modern UI frameworks and patterns through the use of interactive programming session.

UI Lead and front-end developer with aptitude for team dynamics: group coordination, process efficiencies, and individual development. Awarded recognition for Client-Focused Delivery after client feedback on project when leading FED with recently self-taught technology.

Years of experience in UI lead role, conducting engaging technical presentations, and as technical liason for client and internal domain teams. Enforced code quality using best practices such as John DePapa's style guide and BEM on both Agile and Atomic approach projects. Self-motivated and driven as exemplified by creation of D3.js library during bench time and initiation of effective team-building program. Advocate for code stability through unit, integration, functional, or automated visual-diff testing.

### **Putnam Investments**

Javascript UI Developer

JavaScript (jQuery, Highcharts), CSS, HTML, Backbone.js, Modernizr, SVN

🛗 2012 – 2013 | 🗣 Boston, MA

### Innerscope Research Inc.

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2

### **EC Boston**

Web Developer

HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Adobe Contribute compatibility, Photoshop, Illustrator

# </> Code Highlights

## Non-profit Intake App

https://github.com/evandana/keep-ahope

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, Google Cloud, Parse, WebSockets, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel

# Leading a team to create an intake app for a local non-profit. Creating and navigating requirements from stakeholders, including secure data storage and transfer with Google Cloud services. Managing a small group of software engineers who are donating time for this project, ensuring coordinated efforts, timely delivery, and continued engagement.

- Form submission, contact profile search and update, and reports
- Websockets and REST, React / Redux
- Secure sign-in using Google OAuth
- Parse API for server and database interface on Google Cloud

From concept through development to processing results, this livebidding auction and raffle ticket web app exceeded expectations for learning experiences and funds raised. Working with one other developer, we started with domain models, UX whiteboarding, framework choices, and hosting discussions.

 $\label{thm:condition} \mbox{Try the demo-version (https://pmc-2018-demo.firebaseapp.com)} \mbox{ using dummy data.}$ 

- Live bidding: websockets, React / Redux
- Secure sign-in using Google OAuth
- Enforced bidding rules
- Database and hosting using Firebase.io

# **Education History**

# Rochester Institute of Technology

Bachelor, Industrial Design

(2001 – 2005) | **♥** Rochester, NY

### Harvard Extension School

🛗 2013 – 2013 | 🗣 Cambridge, MA

### Coursera.org

 $extbf{ extbf{ extit{ extbf{ extit{min}}}}} ext{ (2012 - 2013) } | extbf{ extit{ extit{ ext{ extit{V}}}} ext{ Stanford University Online}}$ 

# ♠ Activities

# Co-leader of November Project Boston

2014 – 2015 | ♥ Boston, MA

## D3.js Instructor

**PMC Auction App** 

https://pmc-2018-demo.firebaseapp.com

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, WebSockets, Firebase.io, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES6, Babel, Domain Modeling